<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Office 365 on ToastIT</title>
    <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/tags/office-365/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Office 365 on ToastIT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 17:42:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.toastit.dev/tags/office-365/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Learning Story: From Timber to Chocolatey</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/my-learning-story-from-timber-to-chocolatey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 17:42:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/my-learning-story-from-timber-to-chocolatey/</guid>
      <description>My passion has always been tech. Growing up my neighbour&amp;rsquo;s old computers often found their way to me, and I have fond memories of building myself a 486DX2 &amp;ldquo;gaming pc.&amp;rdquo;
That computer was when I leant about the capacitors in power supplies. It turns out that if you&amp;rsquo;re swapping the fan in one of those for one with LEDs in it you probably shouldn&amp;rsquo;t twist the wires together by hand. Who&amp;rsquo;d have known?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Selective with Veeam Backup for Microsoft Office 365</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/veeam-365-selective/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 10:08:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/veeam-365-selective/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s say you&amp;rsquo;re midway through a migration to Office 365. Some of your user&amp;rsquo;s still have mailboxes on-site and others are with Exchange Online. You&amp;rsquo;re not yet advising users to throw data into OneDrive for Business&amp;hellip; but you&amp;rsquo;re also not telling people not to use it.
And, of course, even though you&amp;rsquo;re moving to the cloud you understand that your data is still your problem. With that in mind, you&amp;rsquo;ve got yourself a product to backup your Office 365 data such as Veeam Backup for Microsoft Office 365 (VBO)- yes, there are other products out there, but Veeam is what I know so it&amp;rsquo;s what I use in my &amp;ldquo;hypothetical&amp;rdquo; scenarios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Veeam Backup for Microsoft Office 365 v3.0: It&#39;s Good, Very Good</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/veeam-backup-for-microsoft-office-365-v3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 10:29:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/veeam-backup-for-microsoft-office-365-v3/</guid>
      <description>Towards the end of last week, a tweet with a nice big &amp;ldquo;Veeam Green&amp;rdquo; logo caught my eye.
Veeam Backup for Microsoft Office 365 v3 BETA is here! Looking for your feedback! Get it now via https://t.co/ahLz7QUfKX#veeam#office365#beta— Niels Engelen (@nielsengelen) February 13, 2019A beta preview of the next version of Veeam Backup for Microsoft Office 365? Yes please!
I don&amp;rsquo;t know what I was expecting when I clicked through, but I certainly wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting anything from my wish listto be in the change notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything Is Better with Toast: Getting Build Notifications</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/everything-is-better-with-toast-getting-build-notifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 11:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/everything-is-better-with-toast-getting-build-notifications/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve seen my recent tweetsor my latest blog post, you know that I&amp;rsquo;m on a bit of an Azure Pipelineskick at the moment. The natural progression of this is merging Pipelines with my primary PowerShell/tech interest&amp;hellip; toast.
I realized I was keeping the Pipelines site open as I was pushing commits, waiting to see if the latest build succeeded. Had I broken something? Did I need to pull apart my last set of changes?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Wish List for Veeam Backup for Microsoft Office 365 v3</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/my-wish-list-vbo365/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 08:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/my-wish-list-vbo365/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been testing out Veeam&amp;rsquo;s offering for backing up Office 365. Earlier versions of it could backup Exchange Online but the recently released v2expanded to being able to backup SharePoint Online and OneDrive for Business.
It&amp;rsquo;s a topic that deserves its own post (it&amp;rsquo;s on the list, I swear!), but the reason for needing a product like this needs a quick explanation.
But it&amp;rsquo;s in the cloud, it&amp;rsquo;s already backed up!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pre-Migration Housekeeping: Finding Orphaned Shared Mailboxes</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/orphaned-shared-mailboxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/orphaned-shared-mailboxes/</guid>
      <description>You might be migrating your on-premises Exchange server to the cloud. Maybe you&amp;rsquo;re migrating to a newer version of Exchange. Or maybe you just feel like a bit of a spring clean.
Regardless of why, or if, you want to clean up orphaned shared mailboxes, it is an interesting problem to tackle.
First, in the interest of avoiding scope creep, let&amp;rsquo;s define what we mean by &amp;ldquo;orphaned shared mailbox&amp;rdquo;:
It is a shared mailbox, not a user mailbox that you&amp;rsquo;ve shared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copying Office 365 User Licensing</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/copying-office-365-user-licensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 05:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/copying-office-365-user-licensing/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know if this is an issue for anyone else, or if it&amp;rsquo;s unique to me and the organisation I work for.
As you may knowfrom some of my previous posts, we&amp;rsquo;re dipping our toes into Office 365. This means we&amp;rsquo;re only giving users access to certain features as and when we&amp;rsquo;re ready and we&amp;rsquo;re controlling this by turning on and off parts of their licenses.
As an example of this, checkout this fictional user&amp;rsquo;s license configuration: The Problem Unless I&amp;rsquo;m missing something, there&amp;rsquo;s no decent way of going &amp;ldquo;this user has their license configured how I like it, make this other user (or more likely group of users) look like that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office 365 &amp; PowerShell: Connecting All the Pieces</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/o365-all-the-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/o365-all-the-things/</guid>
      <description>Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve figured out how to connectto each of the Office 365 services, it&amp;rsquo;s time to tie a pretty (PowerShell) blue bow on it. If you just want to skip the writeup and see the result, you can check out the Gist. This Gist may get updates in the future.
Disclaimer The script created in this post is not a complete solution.
It is very much a starting point with no error handling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office 365 &amp; PowerShell: Jacking Into the Matrix</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/o365-connect/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/o365-connect/</guid>
      <description>One thing became apparent very quickly during my recent foray into Office 365: it truly is one big amalgam of bunch of Microsoft products. Just like their on-premises counterparts, each of these products has their own PowerShell interface for management.
Almost every module in the courseware for the &amp;ldquo;Enabling and Managing Office 365&amp;rdquo; course includes a &amp;ldquo;this is the thing you need to download&amp;rdquo; and/or &amp;ldquo;these are the PowerShell commands you need to run to connect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Office 365 Training: Navigating the Minefield</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/o365-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/o365-training/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a lot of research around Office 365 and Azure over the past couple of weeks. As a fan of video training, and as a Pluralsightsubscriber, I&amp;rsquo;ve been devouring the Pluralsight library.
One thing I&amp;rsquo;ve had to become good at very quickly is figuring out the age of the content I&amp;rsquo;m watching and deciding whether it&amp;rsquo;s still relevant.
Unlike traditional (on-premises) technologies, you can&amp;rsquo;t tell from a title whether you&amp;rsquo;re studying the latest version (Exchange 2016 vs Exchange 2013 for example.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
