<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meta on ToastIT</title>
    <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/tags/meta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meta on ToastIT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 17:42:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.toastit.dev/tags/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Learning Story: From Timber to Chocolatey</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/my-learning-story-from-timber-to-chocolatey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 17:42:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/my-learning-story-from-timber-to-chocolatey/</guid>
      <description>My passion has always been tech. Growing up my neighbour&amp;rsquo;s old computers often found their way to me, and I have fond memories of building myself a 486DX2 &amp;ldquo;gaming pc.&amp;rdquo;
That computer was when I leant about the capacitors in power supplies. It turns out that if you&amp;rsquo;re swapping the fan in one of those for one with LEDs in it you probably shouldn&amp;rsquo;t twist the wires together by hand. Who&amp;rsquo;d have known?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Josh King, Sysadmin, and This Is How I Work (During Lockdown)</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/how-i-work-lockdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 09:40:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/how-i-work-lockdown/</guid>
      <description>A couple of years back Adam Bertramorganized several people in the tech space to write &amp;ldquo;How I Work&amp;rdquo; blog posts. These were based on the format set out by Lifehacker, where we had a common set of questions to answer. My previous post is linked below.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been considering an updated post for a while now, especially since I have moved jobs in the interim. The tipping point that finally got this post rolling was New Zealand going into lockdownto work towards eliminating COVID-19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year&#39;s Resolutions - 2020</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/resolutions-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 02:48:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/resolutions-2020/</guid>
      <description>I did one of these New Year&amp;rsquo;s posts back in 2017and 2018&amp;hellip; but for some reason I didn&amp;rsquo;t get around to doing one in 2019 despite calling it outon New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get this train back on track then and have a look back at the past 12 months and publicly list some goals for the next 12.
Looking Back at 2019 Personally and professionally, 2019 was a huge year that I will never forget.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roll Your Sleeves Up, It&#39;s Hacktoberfest Time!</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/hacktoberfest-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 10:37:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/hacktoberfest-2019/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re now about half an hour away from October, at least here in New Zealand, meaning that it&amp;rsquo;s just about time for Hacktoberfest2019 to kick off.
This will be my fourth Hacktoberfest, and with any luck the fourth event t-shirt for my wife to eventually claim (not by my choice though!) I&amp;rsquo;ve written about the event a couple of times in the past, in 2017 and 2018.
What&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;Hacktoberfest&amp;rdquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MVP: OMG</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/mvp-omg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 18:52:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/mvp-omg/</guid>
      <description>Today I&amp;rsquo;m humbled, shocked, and proud to announce that I&amp;rsquo;ve been granted Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Most Valuable Professional (MVP) award in the Cloud and Datacenter Management category. I join an awesome group of people that I&amp;rsquo;ve looked up to (AND STILL DO!) for years.
For those interested in the numbers, New Zealand has a pretty small pool of MVPs that I&amp;rsquo;m jumping into. Excluding myself, there&amp;rsquo;s currently 28 peopleacross all award categories, and only threeunder the Cloud and Datacenter Management banner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Toast to 2018</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/a-toast-to-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 08:20:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/a-toast-to-2018/</guid>
      <description>New Zealand is one of the first countries to see in the New Year. Though I&amp;rsquo;m not usually the type of person to specifically stay awake past midnight to see the calendar change myself. It has, however, got me into a mood to look back on the past year.
In the next day or two, I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing my resolutions for 2019 (including looking back at this year&amp;amp;rsquo;s ones), so this isn&amp;rsquo;t going to be along those lines… instead I wanted to touch on one thing that&amp;rsquo;s been really important to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Need You! #Hacktoberfest</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/hacktoberfest-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 07:42:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/hacktoberfest-2018/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s October again, meaning it&amp;rsquo;s time for Hacktoberfest. It&amp;rsquo;s the fifth time this event has been run, and it&amp;rsquo;s the third time I&amp;rsquo;ve taken part.
The super quick primer on how the event works is:
Register on the Hacktoberfest site, authenticating with your GitHub account. Find projectsyou want to contribute to. Send through five pull requestsduring the month of October. Earn an awesome t-shirt! What&amp;rsquo;s more, Microsoft is also joining Hacktoberfest-ivities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Echo, Echo: Combine System Sounds with your Microphone for Skype for Business Presentations</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/echo-echo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 10:21:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/echo-echo/</guid>
      <description>As with a lot of things I blog about, I don&amp;rsquo;t know how many other people have found themselves looking for solutions to this particular problem.
One of my main PowerShell projects is BurntToast, a module for generating toast notifications. A large part of toasts are their sounds and I&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling with this when doing demos via Skype for Business.
The first time I realised this, I was in the middle of an &amp;ldquo;alarm clock&amp;rdquo; demo and I was making a joke about subjecting the audience to an annoying ringing noise&amp;hellip; only to be told in chat that they couldn&amp;rsquo;t hear it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to TechSnips</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/how-to-techsnips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 05:13:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/how-to-techsnips/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re not aware, I&amp;rsquo;ve recorded a bunch of videosfor Adam Bertram&amp;amp;rsquo;snew learning resource/platform TechSnips. Most of these videos were done prior to the service going live in early June and since then the number of contributors has expanded quite a lot.
I&amp;rsquo;ve had some questions about my setup from those just getting into recording, or getting in a submission. The aim of this post is to document my environment, settings, and workflow with the hope that it can help those wanting to become TechSnips contributors (or heck, even those wanting to get into YouTube or livestreaming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding with Kids Doesn&#39;t &#39;Bug&#39; Me!</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/codebug/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 10:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/codebug/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s not shown in this (very old) video is the pair of air horns that fired off to announce the &amp;ldquo;explosion.&amp;rdquo; Those things were seriously loud, you didn&amp;rsquo;t want them going off while you were in the middle of defusing.
I bring all this up because I have fond memories of hacking out some code and not knowing for sure that it will work until it was loaded up, and run, on the PICAXE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Graphical Example of the Value of Planet PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/a-graphical-example-of-the-value-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 02:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/a-graphical-example-of-the-value-of/</guid>
      <description>Planet PowerShellis an aggregator of community blogs. Looking back at the commit history, it looks like this blog has been hooked up to it for a little over a year.
However the recent move back to Ghostresulted in my posts not coming through to Planet PowerShell. This little hiatus made me realize more than ever the value of the site.
If you have a #PowerShell blog, I can&amp;#39;t overstate how valuable it is to get your feed hooked up to @planetpshell!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Blog Archive Tweets</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/automatic-blog-archive-tweets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 17:54:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/automatic-blog-archive-tweets/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I worked on a PowerShell project &amp;ldquo;for myself.&amp;rdquo; By that I mean creating a script to automate something that I might do myself, in my personal life rather than at work.
This morning I was up at 4 AM, live streamingthe creation of a script to automatically pick a random tweet from my archive and Tweet out a link to it.
Just Give Me the Code!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Makeover - Why, Where, How?</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/blog-makeover/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 18:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/blog-makeover/</guid>
      <description>It feels odd writing this post so soon after documenting my blogging workflow. Over the past two days this blog has migrated from GitHub Pagesto a self hosted Ghostinstall.
A Little History This blog, or at least the earliest posts on it, started on Ghost. This was back when the cost of their hosted services was very cheap. If memory serves, it was around the $5/month mark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get the (Tech)Snip!</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/techsnips-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 01:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/techsnips-intro/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty slack on blog posts over the past two weeks or so. As it is, I&amp;rsquo;m writing this one on my lunch hour and hoping to get it done before it&amp;rsquo;s over.
Why the crunch? In a roundabout way you can blame Adam Bertram.
Adam has been working on a new e-learning service and I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting a fair amount of time into recording content for it, along with many other contributors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Blogging Workflow</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/blog-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/blog-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Coming out of the PowerShell &amp;#43; DevOps Summitand PowerShell Conference Europethere has been a noticeable uptick in new blogs. I&amp;rsquo;ve also noticed a number of people saying &amp;ldquo;I want to get into it&amp;hellip; but need to figure out x and y first.&amp;rdquo;
I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to document my workflow (which is sadly lacking in obvious opportunities for automation) for writing blog posts and a little about the backend this blog runs on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Look Back at #PSHSummit 2018</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/summit2018-hindsight/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 01:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/summit2018-hindsight/</guid>
      <description>After another three flights, and 16 hours in the air, I&amp;rsquo;m back home in New Zealand. I can certainly say that the change in time zones has hit me harder coming back. Going over to Bellevue, I got right into things and felt (for the most part) normal.
Last week I did a blog post for each dayof the PowerShell &amp;#43; DevOps Global Summit, going over what I took part in that day and what my main takeaways were.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Four of #PSHSummit 2018 - Iron Scripter</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/summit2018-day4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/summit2018-day4/</guid>
      <description>That&amp;rsquo;s it. It&amp;rsquo;s over. I&amp;rsquo;ve shaken many hand, met many people, and seen lots of PowerShell.
This&amp;rsquo;ll be the last of my recap posts, and in a couple of days I&amp;rsquo;ll be following up with a &amp;ldquo;this was Summit, and you should be there next year&amp;rdquo; type post.
Please do read the previous three recapsif you haven&amp;rsquo;t already!
Managing Advanced DSC Configurations and Configuration Data Jason Helmick&amp;ldquo;Do you want your morning to be easy?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Three of #PSHSummit 2018 - I Did the Thing</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/summit2018-day3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 06:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/summit2018-day3/</guid>
      <description>What a day.
Today was the reason I was able to be here at Summit. Today was the day I presented in front of about 100 people.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the previous recap posts, please do check them out!
Define, Develop and Deploy DSC Resources Jeff HicksI walked out of this session feeling well armed to start working on my own DSC resources. Until now I&amp;rsquo;ve known I&amp;rsquo;m going to need to do it at some stage but hadn&amp;rsquo;t actually looked into the process of doing so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Two of #PSHSummit 2018 - Getting Smart</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/summit2018-day2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/summit2018-day2/</guid>
      <description>No comments about the plumbing or anything today, having gotten over the initial shock. If you missed yesterday&amp;rsquo;s recap, please do check it out!
As a reminder, I&amp;rsquo;m doing these posts daily during the night after the days&amp;rsquo; sessions. These posts are being done using hand written notes and whatever memory I can spare so please do forgive any glaring errors!
Today&amp;rsquo;s mission was to get the office copy of Windows PowerShell TFMsigned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day One of #PSHSummit 2018 - Bright-Eyed and Bushy-Tailed</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/summit2018-day1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 06:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/summit2018-day1/</guid>
      <description>Why the hell are American toilets so full?
Seriously, this isn&amp;rsquo;t normal. My day started by nearly storming off to reception to complain that they&amp;rsquo;d left the toilet blocked courtesy of the previous guest. Luckily a quick Google short circuited that.
This is really something the travel websites should warn people about!
My hope is that I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing a post like this for each day of the PowerShell &amp;#43; DevOps Global Summit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where the bloody hell are ya?</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/where-are-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/where-are-you/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been somewhat absent lately, both from this blog and YouTube. I did not fully appreciated how much until I&amp;rsquo;d had a message or two asking when my next video will be out.
This seems like a decent excuse for a &amp;ldquo;State of the Blog&amp;rdquo; post covering what I&amp;rsquo;ve been up to recently and what is coming up soon.
Work, work I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how much I can/should say, so I&amp;rsquo;ll keep it somewhat vague.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year&#39;s Resolutions - 2018</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/resolution-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/resolution-2018/</guid>
      <description>Woah, 2017 flew by. I may not have achieved everything on my New Year&amp;amp;rsquo;s Resolutions listfrom last year, but it did help me focus some of my efforts and I&amp;rsquo;m glad I put the list together.
To start off 2018, let&amp;rsquo;s revisit see what (if anything) got completed and set a new list for a new year.
2017, With Hindsight One blog post a month. The only month I didn&amp;rsquo;t do a post was February, but otherwise I&amp;rsquo;m happy with the frequency of posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/psblogweek-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/psblogweek-recap/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday was the end of the latest #PSBlogWeek. It was a great event, with five days worth of awesome PowerShell content coming out!
This is my recap of the week, with links to all of the articles (and bloggers) and my main takeaways.
Monday Automating Chocolatey package internalizing with PowerShellby Dan FranciscusFirst up on Monday, Dan discussed tooling for automating the process of getting Chocolateypackages loaded into your company&amp;rsquo;s private repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October: The Hackiest Month of the Year</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/oct-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/oct-17/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a few things happening this month that officially make it the &amp;ldquo;hackiest&amp;rdquo; month of the year. I know&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s next to no creativity in that title considering it&amp;rsquo;s 100% ripped from one of the month&amp;rsquo;s events.
This is a very short post promoting three things coming up in October. I&amp;rsquo;m excited for them and you should be too!
Summit Session Acceptance The Call for Topicsfor next year&amp;rsquo;s PowerShell and DevOps Global Summitclosed today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The War on Passwords</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/war-on-passwords/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/war-on-passwords/</guid>
      <description>A little over a year ago, the United States National Institute for Standards and Technology (NIST) released a draft of SP 800-63 &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Digital Identity Guidelines&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;. These guidelines were finalized in June. I first found out about NIST&amp;rsquo;s guidelines via Sophosand it really captured my imagination.
(Yes, I&amp;rsquo;m including a few hyperlinks in this post. Consider them references and additional reading if you&amp;rsquo;re want to find out more.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Office 365 Training: Navigating the Minefield</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/o365-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/o365-training/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a lot of research around Office 365 and Azure over the past couple of weeks. As a fan of video training, and as a Pluralsightsubscriber, I&amp;rsquo;ve been devouring the Pluralsight library.
One thing I&amp;rsquo;ve had to become good at very quickly is figuring out the age of the content I&amp;rsquo;m watching and deciding whether it&amp;rsquo;s still relevant.
Unlike traditional (on-premises) technologies, you can&amp;rsquo;t tell from a title whether you&amp;rsquo;re studying the latest version (Exchange 2016 vs Exchange 2013 for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year&#39;s Resolutions - 2017</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/resolution-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 01:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/resolution-2017/</guid>
      <description>New Year&amp;rsquo;s Resolutions are the in thing, right? Since one of mine is to blog more… I might as well turn my resolutions for 2017 into a post. If you&amp;rsquo;ve been here in the past, you know my slant, this list will be PowerShell heavy.
The list, in no particular order despite the numbers </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Josh King, &#39;IT Pro,&#39; and This Is How I Work</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/how-i-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/how-i-work/</guid>
      <description>I follow a bunchof people on GitHub and make checking timeline/feed on there part of my morning habit.
You never know what little gems you&amp;rsquo;ll see come upon, from leaders in your area(s) of interest starring an interesting repo to great coders creating a brand new repo for an awesome new project.
This morning (as in&amp;hellip; the morning of the day I started writing this post) Adam Bertramcreated a new repo called &amp;amp;ldquo;HowIWorkIT&amp;amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
