<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on ToastIT</title>
    <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on ToastIT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 06:54:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Finally, Introducing the First Preview of BurntToast v1</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/finally-introducing-the-first-preview-of-burnttoast-v1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 06:54:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/finally-introducing-the-first-preview-of-burnttoast-v1/</guid>
      <description>Evidently, this last year has gone by very fast. I announcedthat I was starting to work on the re-write of BurntToast that will be released as v1 back in April of 2021 and then promptly&amp;hellip; didn&amp;rsquo;t get around to working on it. With a job change and generally being busy, BurntToast took a back seat for a while there.
But I&amp;rsquo;m glad to say that the first preview release is up on the PowerShell Gallery: BurntToast 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Learning Story: From Timber to Chocolatey</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/my-learning-story-from-timber-to-chocolatey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 17:42:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/my-learning-story-from-timber-to-chocolatey/</guid>
      <description>My passion has always been tech. Growing up my neighbour&amp;rsquo;s old computers often found their way to me, and I have fond memories of building myself a 486DX2 &amp;ldquo;gaming pc.&amp;rdquo;
That computer was when I leant about the capacitors in power supplies. It turns out that if you&amp;rsquo;re swapping the fan in one of those for one with LEDs in it you probably shouldn&amp;rsquo;t twist the wires together by hand. Who&amp;rsquo;d have known?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road to BurntToast v1: Actionable Toast for All!</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/road-to-burnttoast-v1-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 10:03:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/road-to-burnttoast-v1-1/</guid>
      <description>Last year it finally became possible to have actionable toast notificationsin PowerShell&amp;hellip; as long as you were running PowerShell 7.1 and above. This was a super cool development—and I was over the moon with it—but the PowerShell version limitation always loomed and was a downer of a caveat when I was demoing the new feature.
That changes now (or more accurately soon™)!
These &amp;ldquo;Road to BurntToast v1&amp;rdquo; posts are intended to give a preview of some of the features coming in BurntToast v1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crouton #15 - You Can&#39;t Silence Toast</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-15-you-cant-silence-toast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 10:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-15-you-cant-silence-toast/</guid>
      <description>This post has been in the works for a long time now. We&amp;rsquo;re talking almost half a year, and it&amp;rsquo;s been one heck of an uphill battle putting fingers on keys and getting this written. So, what ended up being the catalyst that got this post out into the wild? This morning I woke up to a great tweet from Rob Sewellwith a video about how he&amp;rsquo;s dealing with focus assist so that his toast notification can get through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: PowerShell for Sysadmins</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/review-powershell-sysadmins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 03:33:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/review-powershell-sysadmins/</guid>
      <description>Back in March I received a review copy of Adam Bertram&amp;rsquo;s book, PowerShell for Sysadmins. I immediately tweeted about it and made a smart-arsed comment about treating the timing of my review as a measure of my reading speed.
No Starch Pressprovided a copy of &amp;ldquo;PowerShell for Sysadmins&amp;rdquo; for the purpose of review. Beyond that this post isn&amp;rsquo;t sponsored and thoughts are my own.
Just came in the mail today, @adbertram&#39;s #PowerShellfor SysAdmins from @NoStarchMediaCan&#39;t wait to read it and share my thoughts afterwards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Actionable Toast Notifications, Finally Cracked Them!</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/actionable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 05:54:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/actionable/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been living and breathing toast notifications while building the BurntToastmodule for the past five years. Through this time, they&amp;rsquo;ve been great for delivering information&amp;hellip; or annoying users.
But there has always been a lingering missing piece: &amp;ldquo;Can I do something with these notifications?&amp;rdquo;
Sure, you could always put buttons on your toast notifications. But they were limited to snoozing and dismissing the notification itself or opening files or websites in their default applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Anatomy of Toast</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/anatomy-of-toast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 02:05:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/anatomy-of-toast/</guid>
      <description>Last week, Jeff Hicksasked a questionon the BurntToast repothat made me realize I&amp;rsquo;ve got a lot to work to do documenting the module. I mean, I already knew this, but it was the first time someone had said &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m trying to figure this out using only the built-in help, and it&amp;rsquo;s not working!&amp;rdquo;
One of the main things this highlighted, and a good place to start, was that I&amp;rsquo;ve never written about the how the module&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;advanced&amp;rdquo; functions map to the structure of the resulting XML that Windows uses to display toast notifications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synology Active Backup Suite Review</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/synology-active-backup-suite-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 13:16:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/synology-active-backup-suite-review/</guid>
      <description>Until recently if you asked me about backup providers, I would have talked about the likes of Veeam, StorageCraft, or even Commvault. Why this selection? They are all providers I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with or evaluated in the past, however this does indicate a &amp;ldquo;you don&amp;rsquo;t know what you don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;rdquo; problem.
For example, Synology has always just been a &amp;ldquo;storage&amp;rdquo; company in my mind. While I knew you could run certain workloads on them, I had no idea they have their own suite of backup tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun with Azure Key Vault Part 2: Integration with Azure Functions</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/azure-key-vault-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 03:58:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/azure-key-vault-2/</guid>
      <description>In Part 1of this series we learned how to spin up our own Azure Key Vaultand store a PSCredentialObject in it. We also checked out how to get those credentials back out and use them in our regular scripts.
Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to figure out how we can integrate our Key Vault into Azure Functionsand make use of our credentials there.
Before we continue, make sure you&amp;rsquo;ve followed through the demo in Part 1 or just understand that I&amp;rsquo;ll be reusing Azure resources from that demo without mentioning how to create them here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So *That&#39;s* What OutBuffer Is For!</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/what-outbuffer-is-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/what-outbuffer-is-for/</guid>
      <description>Don Joneshas been talking at a lot of PowerShell User Groups lately. One of the topics he&amp;rsquo;s been covering is little nuggets from his latest (and probably last) PowerShell focused book, Shell of an Idea.
In his talk with the Chicago PowerShell User Groupearlier this month, Don told the story about how OutBuffercame to be&amp;hellip; and what it does. You could see in people&amp;rsquo;s video feeds a collective &amp;ldquo;huh, that&amp;rsquo;s actually really cool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun with Azure Key Vault Part 1: Vault Creation and Storing PSCredential Objects</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/azure-key-vault-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 11:40:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/azure-key-vault-1/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a lot of time recently working on automation solutions in Azure. These solutions use a lot of different Azure services including Logic Apps, Automation Accounts, and Functions.
When working on larger solutions, you often find that you need to use secrets and credentials. If a single solution spans multiple services, it makes sense to store these secrets once in a common place where you can always access them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Josh King, Sysadmin, and This Is How I Work (During Lockdown)</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/how-i-work-lockdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 09:40:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/how-i-work-lockdown/</guid>
      <description>A couple of years back Adam Bertramorganized several people in the tech space to write &amp;ldquo;How I Work&amp;rdquo; blog posts. These were based on the format set out by Lifehacker, where we had a common set of questions to answer. My previous post is linked below.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been considering an updated post for a while now, especially since I have moved jobs in the interim. The tipping point that finally got this post rolling was New Zealand going into lockdownto work towards eliminating COVID-19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staying up to Date on PowerShell Releases with Update Notifications - #PS7Now</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/ps7now-update-notifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 09:47:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/ps7now-update-notifications/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of the #PS7NowPowerShell Blog Week celebrating the general availability launch of PowerShell 7.There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of great content coming out this week from a number of different authors, so make sure you keep an eye on the hashtagover on Twitter or checkout the table at the bottom of this post for direct links!
During this week of blog posts about the latest PowerShell release, you&amp;rsquo;ll have read a lot about many of the new features it delivers and with any luck you&amp;rsquo;ve been sold on it and installed/updated it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring... Nothing? PowerShell 7&#39;s Null Conditional Operators - #PS7Now</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/ps7now-null-conditional/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/ps7now-null-conditional/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of the #PS7NowPowerShell Blog Week celebrating the general availability launch of PowerShell 7.There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of great content coming out this week from a number of different authors, so make sure you keep an eye on the hashtagover on Twitter or checkout the table at the bottom of this post for direct links!
Have you ever found yourself with a variable that may or may not actually exist?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Your Hands on PowerShell 7 - #PS7Now</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/ps7now-installing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/ps7now-installing/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of the #PS7NowPowerShell Blog Week celebrating the general availability launch of PowerShell 7.There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of great content coming out this week from a number of different authors, so make sure you keep an eye on the hashtagover on Twitter or checkout the table at the bottom of this post for direct links!
It&amp;rsquo;s finally here!
It was April of 2019, just after the Generally Available release of PowerShell Core 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Likely We&#39;re Living in a PSSession</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/living-in-a-pssession/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 09:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/living-in-a-pssession/</guid>
      <description>A questioncame up on the PowerShell Microsoft Tech Communitya couple of days ago that got me thinking.
How can we tell if our PowerShell code is running in a PSSession, and what info can we find about the connection itself.
The question itself was based around the fact that the remote sessions had access to a hash table with settings relevant to specific servers and this had to be queried by name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crouton #14 - Fancy Buttons</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-14-buttons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 10:50:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-14-buttons/</guid>
      <description>Toast notifications really shine when you move from just showing information to allowing the user to take some sort of action on it. Unfortunately, our choices when doing this via PowerShell is limited but we can present the user with buttons which can link through to said information in other applications or online.
This is all well and good, and works, but what if these buttons look a little plain?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal Automation: An Early Look</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/universal-automation-early-look/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 11:21:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/universal-automation-early-look/</guid>
      <description>Chances are good that if you&amp;rsquo;ve been around any part of the PowerShell community during the past couple of years, you&amp;rsquo;ve at least heard of Universal Dashboard(UD).
If, somehow, you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of it yet UD is a product from Ironman Software, which is headed up by Adam Driscoll. It started as a tool focused on easily spinning up dashboards using PowerShell and has since developed into a full-on web framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell&#39;s Secret Wildcard</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/powershells-secret-wildcard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 10:07:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/powershells-secret-wildcard/</guid>
      <description>A couple of days ago I found myself needing to match text entries between two systems. The entries had a bunch of meta data, but the only thing I could use for the match was the text itself.
In one system, the text might read:
&amp;quot;This text is super important.&amp;quot; The second system had that same text, but with a little extra added to it but not in a predictable format:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year&#39;s Resolutions - 2020</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/resolutions-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 02:48:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/resolutions-2020/</guid>
      <description>I did one of these New Year&amp;rsquo;s posts back in 2017and 2018&amp;hellip; but for some reason I didn&amp;rsquo;t get around to doing one in 2019 despite calling it outon New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get this train back on track then and have a look back at the past 12 months and publicly list some goals for the next 12.
Looking Back at 2019 Personally and professionally, 2019 was a huge year that I will never forget.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Devops for PowerShell - #AzureAdventCalendar 2019 Day 15</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/azure-devops-for-powershell-azureadventcalendar-2019-day-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:21:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/azure-devops-for-powershell-azureadventcalendar-2019-day-15/</guid>
      <description>Did you grow up with advent calendars in the lead up to Christmas each year? My kids have taken up the tradition with a great passion (the chocolate may have something to do with this), which makes me all sorts of jealous.
Luckily there&amp;rsquo;s another option for those that may have - as far as you&amp;rsquo;ll admit to the office - outgrown chocolate based advent calendars: the Azure Advent Calendar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Sense of Data: The Matrix</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/making-sense-of-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 09:39:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/making-sense-of-data/</guid>
      <description>PowerShell is a, well, powerhouse when it comes to collecting data. Sometimes however it can feel like you&amp;rsquo;re swimming in said data and you can&amp;rsquo;t quite find the right way to understand that data yourself, let alone hand that data off to someone else and it actually be useful.
Enter the Matrix One of the methods I&amp;rsquo;ve been using lately is a matrix. These matrixes are a spreadsheet with one set of &amp;ldquo;things&amp;rdquo; along the top, another set down the left, and some sort of mark in the middle to show when they intersect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tired of Massive &#39;like&#39; Operator Chains? Rub a Little RegEx on It</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/like-operator-chains/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 09:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/like-operator-chains/</guid>
      <description>I was recently writing a PowerShell script and found myself needing to check an input value against a laundry list of criteria. That criteria could have been anywhere in the input value, so out of habit I started writing something that looked like this:
$Input = &#39;This is an example string. It demonstrates &amp;quot;stuff.&amp;quot;&#39; if ($Input -like &#39;*example*&#39; -or $Input -like &#39;*demo*&#39; -or $Input -like &#39;*more criteria*&#39; -or $Input -like &#39;*when will this end?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crouton #13 - Hitting Snooze</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-13-hitting-snooze/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 09:09:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-13-hitting-snooze/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year an issuecame through on the BurntToast GitHub repoabout binding custom snooze times to a toast&amp;rsquo;s snooze button.
If my documentation was a little more complete, the answer would have been in the built in help&amp;hellip; but I&amp;rsquo;m still working on that (while hanging my head in shame!) This post is the first step in getting something written on the topic of Snoozing and/or Dismissing toast notifications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Ternary Operator Revisit: Can It Elseif?</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/quick-ternary-operator-revisit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 04:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/quick-ternary-operator-revisit/</guid>
      <description>It was a little over a week ago that I first started looking into the Ternary Operator, which is being added in PowerShell 7. I came away from my initial experimentation looking forward to being able to use it for trivial conditional logic when I can guarantee that the code will only need to run on the new version of PowerShell.
Why trivial? As someone that&amp;rsquo;s not used the ternary operator in the past, reading it doesn&amp;rsquo;t come naturally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roll Your Sleeves Up, It&#39;s Hacktoberfest Time!</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/hacktoberfest-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 10:37:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/hacktoberfest-2019/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re now about half an hour away from October, at least here in New Zealand, meaning that it&amp;rsquo;s just about time for Hacktoberfest2019 to kick off.
This will be my fourth Hacktoberfest, and with any luck the fourth event t-shirt for my wife to eventually claim (not by my choice though!) I&amp;rsquo;ve written about the event a couple of times in the past, in 2017 and 2018.
What&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;Hacktoberfest&amp;rdquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Familiar with the Ternary Operator in PowerShell 7</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/ternary-operator-powershell-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 09:17:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/ternary-operator-powershell-7/</guid>
      <description>It was only a fortnight ago that I was digging into the preview 3release of PowerShell 7 looking at the new parallel for each loop feature. Since then preview 4has been released, and that introduced yet another feature I want to have a closer look at: the ternary operator.
What&amp;rsquo;s a Ternary? The ternary operator is present in many programming languages and, according to the PowerShell team&amp;amp;rsquo;s DevBlogon this release, is quite popular with C# developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure DevOps Pipelines Tune Up: Templates and Centralization</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/azure-pipelines-tune-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 22:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/azure-pipelines-tune-up/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend I wrote two plugins for PoshBot: Joker&amp;amp; Sentiment. Both of these were equipped with my standard Azure DevOps Pipelines treatment for testing, building, and releasing them to the PowerShell Gallery. Doing two in quick succession made me realize just how repetitive my pipelines actually are.
It was interesting timing then, that during the week I came across a post by Justin Yooabout refactoring these pipelines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can Parallel For Each Loops in PowerShell 7 Tear Me Away from PoshRSJob?</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/powershell7-foreach-parallel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 09:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/powershell7-foreach-parallel/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a long time user of Boe Prox&amp;amp;rsquo;smodule, PoshRSJob. For the uninitiated, this module lets you easily add a touch of parallelizationto your PowerShell scripts. It allows you to spin up runspaces without the headache of having to try and figure them out yourself.
Why Bother? If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever found yourself needing to reach out onto your network and find a particular file on each of 500 different workstations you have a couple of options for how to tackle the job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MVP: OMG</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/mvp-omg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 18:52:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/mvp-omg/</guid>
      <description>Today I&amp;rsquo;m humbled, shocked, and proud to announce that I&amp;rsquo;ve been granted Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Most Valuable Professional (MVP) award in the Cloud and Datacenter Management category. I join an awesome group of people that I&amp;rsquo;ve looked up to (AND STILL DO!) for years.
For those interested in the numbers, New Zealand has a pretty small pool of MVPs that I&amp;rsquo;m jumping into. Excluding myself, there&amp;rsquo;s currently 28 peopleacross all award categories, and only threeunder the Cloud and Datacenter Management banner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crouton #12 - Toasting in Many Tongues (Tōhi o nga reo maha)</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 11:09:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-12/</guid>
      <description>Last time we talkedtoast notifications, we covered how you can gracefully update their content. This was achieved through a process called data binding where you specify placeholder &amp;ldquo;anchors&amp;rdquo; in your notification in place of the actual text which then maps through to the text to be displayed in a hashtable.
There&amp;rsquo;s another use case for this data binding mechanism which I&amp;rsquo;m very excited about: localization.
First, an Apology I&amp;rsquo;ll be using Māorias a non-English language in this post, but I&amp;rsquo;m ashamed to say that my te reo isn&amp;rsquo;t too sharp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Normalizing Phone Numbers, Easier with Regex</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/normalizing-phone-numbers-easier-with-regex/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 11:16:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/normalizing-phone-numbers-easier-with-regex/</guid>
      <description>For the longest time, Regexhas been similar to black magic in my mind. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen these expressions used by (scripting) wizard to do amazing things, but I have never been able to wrap my head around them.
The best I&amp;rsquo;d managed in the past was to Google a pattern that matched what I was looking for and stole re-purposed them in my scripts without much understanding of how or why it actually worked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crouton #11 - Updating Toast Notifications, Gracefully</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 10:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-11/</guid>
      <description>Wow, it feels like forever since I was last able to sit down and write a blog post. What better way to get back into the swing of things than to make good on the post I alluded to in my last Crouton: Updatable Toast Notifications.
The Old Method Prior to version 0.7.0 of BurntToastyou had one option for updating the content of a toast. That options was what I&amp;rsquo;d probably refer to as &amp;ldquo;Brute Force.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disjointed Thoughts on Veeam Backup for Office 365 v3</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/veeam-onedrive-selective/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 08:38:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/veeam-onedrive-selective/</guid>
      <description>A while back, while it was in beta, I sung the praises of Veeam Backup for Office 365 v3(VBO). Since then this update has been officially released. I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet (&amp;hellip; at the time of writing) had the opportunity to update my production install, although I am champing at the bit to do so, so I&amp;rsquo;ve continued to poke around the beta until the license expires.
Before diving into this, I want to highlight that this is going to be a little different from my normal posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crouton #10 - Cold Shoulder (Taps)</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 09:49:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-10/</guid>
      <description>Last night I pushed go on a big update to BurntToast, bringing the version number up to 0.7.0.
The features present in this update were done a short while ago, and then I hit a bit of a slow down when it came to cleaning up the documentation and help. Instead of delaying getting these features out into the wild, I elected to push the update with &amp;ldquo;enough&amp;rdquo; help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Selective with Veeam Backup for Microsoft Office 365</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/veeam-365-selective/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 10:08:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/veeam-365-selective/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s say you&amp;rsquo;re midway through a migration to Office 365. Some of your user&amp;rsquo;s still have mailboxes on-site and others are with Exchange Online. You&amp;rsquo;re not yet advising users to throw data into OneDrive for Business&amp;hellip; but you&amp;rsquo;re also not telling people not to use it.
And, of course, even though you&amp;rsquo;re moving to the cloud you understand that your data is still your problem. With that in mind, you&amp;rsquo;ve got yourself a product to backup your Office 365 data such as Veeam Backup for Microsoft Office 365 (VBO)- yes, there are other products out there, but Veeam is what I know so it&amp;rsquo;s what I use in my &amp;ldquo;hypothetical&amp;rdquo; scenarios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving My Automatic Blog Archive Tweets to Azure Functions</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/blog-archive-to-azure-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 21:08:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/blog-archive-to-azure-function/</guid>
      <description>Mid way through last year I live streamed and bloggedthe creation of a script that automatically sends out &amp;ldquo;blog archive&amp;rdquo; tweets. It&amp;rsquo;s been working well, and has been resurfacing topics that I sometimes forget I&amp;rsquo;ve written.
Until today, it&amp;rsquo;d been running on my home server&amp;hellip; but why?
It&amp;rsquo;s a fairly simple script, with no need to run on an actual server, let alone that specific one. It seems like the perfect script to move to a serverless service and learn how to use them in practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Veeam Backup for Microsoft Office 365 v3.0: It&#39;s Good, Very Good</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/veeam-backup-for-microsoft-office-365-v3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 10:29:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/veeam-backup-for-microsoft-office-365-v3/</guid>
      <description>Towards the end of last week, a tweet with a nice big &amp;ldquo;Veeam Green&amp;rdquo; logo caught my eye.
Veeam Backup for Microsoft Office 365 v3 BETA is here! Looking for your feedback! Get it now via https://t.co/ahLz7QUfKX#veeam#office365#beta— Niels Engelen (@nielsengelen) February 13, 2019A beta preview of the next version of Veeam Backup for Microsoft Office 365? Yes please!
I don&amp;rsquo;t know what I was expecting when I clicked through, but I certainly wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting anything from my wish listto be in the change notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Failed My Way to Success with Azure Pipelines - Part 2: Release</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/how-i-failed-my-way-to-success-with-azure-pipelines-part-2-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 09:08:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/how-i-failed-my-way-to-success-with-azure-pipelines-part-2-release/</guid>
      <description>Despite the name of this series of posts, the first one didn&amp;rsquo;t contain too many fails. Credit where credit is due, that&amp;rsquo;s because of Tyler&amp;amp;rsquo;sground work on the build pipeline front. When it came to release pipelines I was flying blind, bring on the fails!
Missed part one of this series? Read it first!If You Don&amp;rsquo;t Clean Your Room, You Won&amp;rsquo;t Get Any YAML Unlike the build pipelines we&amp;rsquo;ve just finished with, there is (currently) no support to configure release pipelines via YAML.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RSAT as a Feature: I Thought I Was Going to Love It, Until I Saw It in Action</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/rsat-as-a-feature-i-thought-i-was-going-to-love-it-until-i-saw-it-in-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 08:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/rsat-as-a-feature-i-thought-i-was-going-to-love-it-until-i-saw-it-in-action/</guid>
      <description>Ok, that title may be a little hyperbolic. It&amp;rsquo;s not like I hate the experience of having the Remote Server Administration Tools (RSAT) installable as a feature rather than a standalone download. It&amp;rsquo;s just that it&amp;rsquo;s not what I&amp;rsquo;d imagine when I first heard about it.
But what was I expecting? I thought we&amp;rsquo;d still be going into the classic Windows Features interface, just without the need to install the binaries (manually) before hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything Is Better with Toast: Getting Build Notifications</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/everything-is-better-with-toast-getting-build-notifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 11:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/everything-is-better-with-toast-getting-build-notifications/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve seen my recent tweetsor my latest blog post, you know that I&amp;rsquo;m on a bit of an Azure Pipelineskick at the moment. The natural progression of this is merging Pipelines with my primary PowerShell/tech interest&amp;hellip; toast.
I realized I was keeping the Pipelines site open as I was pushing commits, waiting to see if the latest build succeeded. Had I broken something? Did I need to pull apart my last set of changes?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Failed My Way to Success with Azure Pipelines - Part 1: Build</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/how-i-failed-my-way-to-success-with-azure-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 11:38:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/how-i-failed-my-way-to-success-with-azure-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>When something new and shiny comes out, I find myself needing it to &amp;ldquo;click&amp;rdquo; with me before I go &amp;ldquo;right, yes, I need to use that.&amp;rdquo;
This isn&amp;rsquo;t to say I don&amp;rsquo;t see the value in it. I just assume that it&amp;rsquo;s for someone other than me.
Azure Pipelines, part of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s DevOps Services, was in that box for a long time. I assumed it was way out of my league, that it could work for PowerShell projects but ones that are much bigger than what I work on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crouton #8 Redux - Now with a More Complete Example</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-8-redux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 05:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-8-redux/</guid>
      <description>It feels like only yesterday that I wrote Crouton #8, but it&amp;rsquo;s actually been over four months. Obviously, time has been flying by recently. I&amp;rsquo;m revisiting the topic following a question from @jkrhrton Twitter asking for example files, and I figured it might make for a decent mini blog post.
@WindosNZDo you have any example files relating to your &#39;Crouton #8&#39; blog post? I just can&#39;t quite wrap my head around it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Toast to 2018</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/a-toast-to-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 08:20:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/a-toast-to-2018/</guid>
      <description>New Zealand is one of the first countries to see in the New Year. Though I&amp;rsquo;m not usually the type of person to specifically stay awake past midnight to see the calendar change myself. It has, however, got me into a mood to look back on the past year.
In the next day or two, I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing my resolutions for 2019 (including looking back at this year&amp;amp;rsquo;s ones), so this isn&amp;rsquo;t going to be along those lines… instead I wanted to touch on one thing that&amp;rsquo;s been really important to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cutting My Teeth on PowerShell Flavoured GitHub Actions</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/powershell-flavoured-github-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 11:46:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/powershell-flavoured-github-actions/</guid>
      <description>Whew, I haven&amp;rsquo;t written a blog in a while now. I&amp;rsquo;ve missed it! I&amp;rsquo;ll have a soppy post in the new year about where I&amp;rsquo;ve been and what&amp;rsquo;s been keeping me so busy, but today I wanted to jot down some notes about a cool thing I started diving into at lunch.
GitHubannounced a new feature a while back, Actions, an awesome tool for creating workflows to give your repositories super powers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Wish List for Veeam Backup for Microsoft Office 365 v3</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/my-wish-list-vbo365/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 08:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/my-wish-list-vbo365/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been testing out Veeam&amp;rsquo;s offering for backing up Office 365. Earlier versions of it could backup Exchange Online but the recently released v2expanded to being able to backup SharePoint Online and OneDrive for Business.
It&amp;rsquo;s a topic that deserves its own post (it&amp;rsquo;s on the list, I swear!), but the reason for needing a product like this needs a quick explanation.
But it&amp;rsquo;s in the cloud, it&amp;rsquo;s already backed up!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crouton #9 - Free, with Attribution</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-9-attribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 15:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-9-attribution/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of hidden gems within the toast notification framework that allow you to tailor your toasts to your taste.
One of these features that I haven&amp;rsquo;t given enough love to (so much so, that it isn&amp;rsquo;t even properly implemented in BurntToastyet) is attribution.
It&amp;rsquo;s a small thing (literally), but attribution text let&amp;rsquo;s you provide more context about the source of your notification. The official documentation demonstrates using this text to identify the communication channel that a message was received on, such as &amp;ldquo;Via SMS&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Need You! #Hacktoberfest</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/hacktoberfest-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 07:42:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/hacktoberfest-2018/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s October again, meaning it&amp;rsquo;s time for Hacktoberfest. It&amp;rsquo;s the fifth time this event has been run, and it&amp;rsquo;s the third time I&amp;rsquo;ve taken part.
The super quick primer on how the event works is:
Register on the Hacktoberfest site, authenticating with your GitHub account. Find projectsyou want to contribute to. Send through five pull requestsduring the month of October. Earn an awesome t-shirt! What&amp;rsquo;s more, Microsoft is also joining Hacktoberfest-ivities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pre-Migration Housekeeping: Finding Orphaned Shared Mailboxes</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/orphaned-shared-mailboxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/orphaned-shared-mailboxes/</guid>
      <description>You might be migrating your on-premises Exchange server to the cloud. Maybe you&amp;rsquo;re migrating to a newer version of Exchange. Or maybe you just feel like a bit of a spring clean.
Regardless of why, or if, you want to clean up orphaned shared mailboxes, it is an interesting problem to tackle.
First, in the interest of avoiding scope creep, let&amp;rsquo;s define what we mean by &amp;ldquo;orphaned shared mailbox&amp;rdquo;:
It is a shared mailbox, not a user mailbox that you&amp;rsquo;ve shared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crouton #8 - I like Your Code, but I Don&#39;t Want It on All My Computers</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-8-i-like-your-code-but-i-dont-want-it-on-all-my-computers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 05:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-8-i-like-your-code-but-i-dont-want-it-on-all-my-computers/</guid>
      <description>BurntToasthas been downloaded over 13,000 times. 1,400of these were just in the past six weeks. While I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to chat with anyone responsible for these numbers, I have to assume it&amp;rsquo;s because someone out there is deploying the module across a reasonably large network for notifications on numerous end points.
This thought ties in with a question I got recently. If you do want to use toast notifications across your network, do you have to deploy the module everywhere?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Echo, Echo: Combine System Sounds with your Microphone for Skype for Business Presentations</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/echo-echo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 10:21:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/echo-echo/</guid>
      <description>As with a lot of things I blog about, I don&amp;rsquo;t know how many other people have found themselves looking for solutions to this particular problem.
One of my main PowerShell projects is BurntToast, a module for generating toast notifications. A large part of toasts are their sounds and I&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling with this when doing demos via Skype for Business.
The first time I realised this, I was in the middle of an &amp;ldquo;alarm clock&amp;rdquo; demo and I was making a joke about subjecting the audience to an annoying ringing noise&amp;hellip; only to be told in chat that they couldn&amp;rsquo;t hear it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to TechSnips</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/how-to-techsnips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 05:13:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/how-to-techsnips/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re not aware, I&amp;rsquo;ve recorded a bunch of videosfor Adam Bertram&amp;amp;rsquo;snew learning resource/platform TechSnips. Most of these videos were done prior to the service going live in early June and since then the number of contributors has expanded quite a lot.
I&amp;rsquo;ve had some questions about my setup from those just getting into recording, or getting in a submission. The aim of this post is to document my environment, settings, and workflow with the hope that it can help those wanting to become TechSnips contributors (or heck, even those wanting to get into YouTube or livestreaming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copying Office 365 User Licensing</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/copying-office-365-user-licensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 05:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/copying-office-365-user-licensing/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know if this is an issue for anyone else, or if it&amp;rsquo;s unique to me and the organisation I work for.
As you may knowfrom some of my previous posts, we&amp;rsquo;re dipping our toes into Office 365. This means we&amp;rsquo;re only giving users access to certain features as and when we&amp;rsquo;re ready and we&amp;rsquo;re controlling this by turning on and off parts of their licenses.
As an example of this, checkout this fictional user&amp;rsquo;s license configuration: The Problem Unless I&amp;rsquo;m missing something, there&amp;rsquo;s no decent way of going &amp;ldquo;this user has their license configured how I like it, make this other user (or more likely group of users) look like that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Credentials Safe, But Accessible</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/safe-credentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 10:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/safe-credentials/</guid>
      <description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to &amp;ldquo;step back&amp;rdquo; a little bit and consider the tools that I use every day. Why do I use them, are they the best I could be using, and are there any lessons I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt along the way that I can bass on?
This is partially why I&amp;rsquo;ve started writing about scheduled jobs, and why you&amp;rsquo;ll likely see posts in the future about PoshRSJob(spoilers!)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PS Scheduled Jobs: Exploring Your Options</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/exploring-your-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 03:12:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/exploring-your-options/</guid>
      <description>There are a total of 13 different options you can configure using the New-ScheduledJobOption and Set-ScheduledJobOption cmdlets. All of these options have a default value, and the resulting object will list out each of them. If you do not configure an option, it is assumed that you&amp;rsquo;re happy with the default.
One example of this that may catch you out if you are working on a laptop is StartIfOnBatteries. This defaults to false and means that if your laptop isn&amp;rsquo;t plugged into AC power, your scheduled job will not run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fully Qualified Path to PowerShell.exe in Scheduled Jobs?</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/scheduled-job-qualified/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 07:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/scheduled-job-qualified/</guid>
      <description>Two things before we jump into this post:
Yes, I struggled for literally minutes with the capitalization of &amp;ldquo;PowerShell.exe&amp;rdquo; in the title. No, I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to be writing about Windows PowerShell scheduled jobs again so soon. The reason I am writing about scheduled jobs is because of an awesome question from Twitter.
Is it possible to set the action to have a fully qualified path to powershell.exe? This is one of our security teams requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell Orchestration with Scheduled Jobs - The Start of a Series</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/powershell-orchestration-with-scheduled-jobs-the-start-of-a-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 10:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/powershell-orchestration-with-scheduled-jobs-the-start-of-a-series/</guid>
      <description>I love &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Windows PowerShell scheduled jobs&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;. It occurred to me recently that I&amp;rsquo;ve used them in plenty of posts, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never really delved into them any deeper than getting a specific task sorted.
This is the first in a series of posts, the aim of which is to make you love them too.
You may have noticed that I referenced scheduled jobs with the Windows PowerShell prefix above. That was not a mistake, or subconscious twitch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding with Kids Doesn&#39;t &#39;Bug&#39; Me!</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/codebug/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 10:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/codebug/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s not shown in this (very old) video is the pair of air horns that fired off to announce the &amp;ldquo;explosion.&amp;rdquo; Those things were seriously loud, you didn&amp;rsquo;t want them going off while you were in the middle of defusing.
I bring all this up because I have fond memories of hacking out some code and not knowing for sure that it will work until it was loaded up, and run, on the PICAXE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Graphical Example of the Value of Planet PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/a-graphical-example-of-the-value-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 02:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/a-graphical-example-of-the-value-of/</guid>
      <description>Planet PowerShellis an aggregator of community blogs. Looking back at the commit history, it looks like this blog has been hooked up to it for a little over a year.
However the recent move back to Ghostresulted in my posts not coming through to Planet PowerShell. This little hiatus made me realize more than ever the value of the site.
If you have a #PowerShell blog, I can&amp;#39;t overstate how valuable it is to get your feed hooked up to @planetpshell!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Blog Archive Tweets</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/automatic-blog-archive-tweets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 17:54:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/automatic-blog-archive-tweets/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I worked on a PowerShell project &amp;ldquo;for myself.&amp;rdquo; By that I mean creating a script to automate something that I might do myself, in my personal life rather than at work.
This morning I was up at 4 AM, live streamingthe creation of a script to automatically pick a random tweet from my archive and Tweet out a link to it.
Just Give Me the Code!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloading an Image for Local Use</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/downloading-an-image-for-local-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 00:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/downloading-an-image-for-local-use/</guid>
      <description>During my latest livestream, after failing at what I intended to do, we got onto enabling the ability to use pictures from the Internet in toast notifications. All of the documentation for the UWP Toolkit suggests this should just work, but unfortunately it didn&amp;rsquo;t in practice.
Rather than changing the code, and documentation, to explicitly not make this work from within the module we set out to enable this functionality ourselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Makeover - Why, Where, How?</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/blog-makeover/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 18:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/blog-makeover/</guid>
      <description>It feels odd writing this post so soon after documenting my blogging workflow. Over the past two days this blog has migrated from GitHub Pagesto a self hosted Ghostinstall.
A Little History This blog, or at least the earliest posts on it, started on Ghost. This was back when the cost of their hosted services was very cheap. If memory serves, it was around the $5/month mark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get the (Tech)Snip!</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/techsnips-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 01:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/techsnips-intro/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty slack on blog posts over the past two weeks or so. As it is, I&amp;rsquo;m writing this one on my lunch hour and hoping to get it done before it&amp;rsquo;s over.
Why the crunch? In a roundabout way you can blame Adam Bertram.
Adam has been working on a new e-learning service and I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting a fair amount of time into recording content for it, along with many other contributors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crouton #7 – Superhero Landing</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-heroimages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 02:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-heroimages/</guid>
      <description>Ever find yourself needing to get an image up on your screen in a timely manner?
Yeah, me neither. But if you do find this to be the case then you can use a Toast Notification to do the job.
As with all of these &amp;ldquo;Crouton&amp;rdquo; posts, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to have the BurntToastmodule installed in order to follow along.
The Scenario Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have CCTV cameras outside your server rooms, and you want to get a snapshot when they pickup movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Blogging Workflow</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/blog-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/blog-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Coming out of the PowerShell &amp;#43; DevOps Summitand PowerShell Conference Europethere has been a noticeable uptick in new blogs. I&amp;rsquo;ve also noticed a number of people saying &amp;ldquo;I want to get into it&amp;hellip; but need to figure out x and y first.&amp;rdquo;
I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to document my workflow (which is sadly lacking in obvious opportunities for automation) for writing blog posts and a little about the backend this blog runs on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All I Want Is a Damned CSV!</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/ps-csv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/ps-csv/</guid>
      <description>Spurred on by a common issue that comes up on Twitter from time to time, this will be a rather short post about CSVs and PowerShell.
What&amp;rsquo;s the Issue? Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have an array of strings.
$Servers = @( &#39;AD1&#39;, &#39;FILE1&#39;, &#39;DB1&#39;, &#39;APP1&#39; ) You want to save these to disk. CSVs are pretty handy, right? And there is a cmdlet that&amp;rsquo;ll handle this for you!
$Servers | Export-Csv -Path C:\temp\servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Look Back at #PSHSummit 2018</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/summit2018-hindsight/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 01:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/summit2018-hindsight/</guid>
      <description>After another three flights, and 16 hours in the air, I&amp;rsquo;m back home in New Zealand. I can certainly say that the change in time zones has hit me harder coming back. Going over to Bellevue, I got right into things and felt (for the most part) normal.
Last week I did a blog post for each dayof the PowerShell &amp;#43; DevOps Global Summit, going over what I took part in that day and what my main takeaways were.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Four of #PSHSummit 2018 - Iron Scripter</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/summit2018-day4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/summit2018-day4/</guid>
      <description>That&amp;rsquo;s it. It&amp;rsquo;s over. I&amp;rsquo;ve shaken many hand, met many people, and seen lots of PowerShell.
This&amp;rsquo;ll be the last of my recap posts, and in a couple of days I&amp;rsquo;ll be following up with a &amp;ldquo;this was Summit, and you should be there next year&amp;rdquo; type post.
Please do read the previous three recapsif you haven&amp;rsquo;t already!
Managing Advanced DSC Configurations and Configuration Data Jason Helmick&amp;ldquo;Do you want your morning to be easy?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Three of #PSHSummit 2018 - I Did the Thing</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/summit2018-day3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 06:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/summit2018-day3/</guid>
      <description>What a day.
Today was the reason I was able to be here at Summit. Today was the day I presented in front of about 100 people.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the previous recap posts, please do check them out!
Define, Develop and Deploy DSC Resources Jeff HicksI walked out of this session feeling well armed to start working on my own DSC resources. Until now I&amp;rsquo;ve known I&amp;rsquo;m going to need to do it at some stage but hadn&amp;rsquo;t actually looked into the process of doing so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Two of #PSHSummit 2018 - Getting Smart</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/summit2018-day2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/summit2018-day2/</guid>
      <description>No comments about the plumbing or anything today, having gotten over the initial shock. If you missed yesterday&amp;rsquo;s recap, please do check it out!
As a reminder, I&amp;rsquo;m doing these posts daily during the night after the days&amp;rsquo; sessions. These posts are being done using hand written notes and whatever memory I can spare so please do forgive any glaring errors!
Today&amp;rsquo;s mission was to get the office copy of Windows PowerShell TFMsigned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day One of #PSHSummit 2018 - Bright-Eyed and Bushy-Tailed</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/summit2018-day1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 06:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/summit2018-day1/</guid>
      <description>Why the hell are American toilets so full?
Seriously, this isn&amp;rsquo;t normal. My day started by nearly storming off to reception to complain that they&amp;rsquo;d left the toilet blocked courtesy of the previous guest. Luckily a quick Google short circuited that.
This is really something the travel websites should warn people about!
My hope is that I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing a post like this for each day of the PowerShell &amp;#43; DevOps Global Summit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crouton #6 – Dance to Your Own Beat</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-sounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-sounds/</guid>
      <description>BurntToastis long overdue an update (sorry!) and right alongside that is the project&amp;rsquo;s need for better documentation.
I recently got a tweet about how to get a toast to play custom sound. I really like getting messages like this for two reasons: it gives me a glimpse into how people are using the module and it also focuses my documentation efforts on something that might actually be useful.
@WindosNZhi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Veeam: My First Virtual Lab</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/veeam-my-first-virtual-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/veeam-my-first-virtual-lab/</guid>
      <description>Over the last day or so I&amp;rsquo;ve been setting up a sandbox/virtual lab which leverages our Veeam backups. We&amp;rsquo;ve been using SureBackupfor automatic restore point verification, but a large software update that&amp;rsquo;s coming down the pipeline was a really good excuse to get a semi-persistent lab running.
This post goes through the process of setting up a lab from start to finish. I&amp;rsquo;d found posts that went through parts of the process, usually focusing on the trickier parts, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t really find any real world, end-to-end walkthroughs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Need PowerShell Help? Use #PSHelp!</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/pshelp-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/pshelp-twitter/</guid>
      <description>Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about how much I enjoytaking part in the monthly #PSTweetChatevent on Twitter and how awesome the PowerShell community on there is (seriously, y&amp;rsquo;all rock!)
If possible, I&amp;rsquo;d love to try and help steer that amazing community towards a hashtag specifically for helping with short (hopefully) PowerShell problems.
There&amp;rsquo;s Always a Hashtag As it turns out, there&amp;rsquo;s already a hashtag which sees some use: #PSHelpI&amp;rsquo;ve added this to my TweetDeck layout and will be keeping an eye on it from now on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where the bloody hell are ya?</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/where-are-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/where-are-you/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been somewhat absent lately, both from this blog and YouTube. I did not fully appreciated how much until I&amp;rsquo;d had a message or two asking when my next video will be out.
This seems like a decent excuse for a &amp;ldquo;State of the Blog&amp;rdquo; post covering what I&amp;rsquo;ve been up to recently and what is coming up soon.
Work, work I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how much I can/should say, so I&amp;rsquo;ll keep it somewhat vague.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY AppId and WiX, for Tasty Toast</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/burnttoast-wix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/burnttoast-wix/</guid>
      <description>It has certainly taken a lot longer to get this post out than I&amp;rsquo;d hoped. Better late than never, I guess?
My last postshowed off the results I had using the WiX Toolsetto create a Start Menu shortcut with the necessary metadata embedded to get toasts working properly in newer versions of Windows 10.
This time around, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through how to create your own installer.
Get WiX Given we&amp;rsquo;ll be using it very soon, the first thing you should do is grab the latest stable release of the WiX Toolset(they&amp;rsquo;ll link you off to the GitHub repo, download the exe file).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BurntToast &#43; AppId = It&#39;s Working!</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/burnttoast-appid-installer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 07:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/burnttoast-appid-installer/</guid>
      <description>I can&amp;rsquo;t tell you how happy I am to be writing this post.
AppId&amp;rsquo;s have been a thorn in my sidefor a long time. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using a loophole to get toasts displayed which recent versions of Windows 10 closed. This resulted in my removing the ability to easily set a custom AppId.
The fix in the short term was to hard code BurntToast&amp;rsquo;s default AppId to that of powershell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crouton #5 – Password Expiry Warning</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-password/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-password/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Something is wrong with my computer. Outlook is asking me for my password?!&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Let me look&amp;hellip; Oh, it looks like your password expired about 15 minutes ago.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;How the heck did that happen, isn&amp;rsquo;t the system meant to give me some warning?&amp;rdquo;
Invisible Expiry Reminders I don&amp;rsquo;t often get these calls personally any more, but I do overhear them. There&amp;rsquo;s no point trying to tell your user that the &amp;lsquo;system&amp;rsquo; did warn them (for three days by default).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Updates: Putting Update Avoidance to Bed</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/wu-put-to-bed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/wu-put-to-bed/</guid>
      <description>This will be my fourth, and final, poston the topic of stopping updates from automatically installing on Windows 10.
If you&amp;rsquo;re wanting to skip to the punch line:
Yes, you can prevent updates from being installed, No, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t prevent updates from being installed, Do updates on your time, and don&amp;rsquo;t leave them sitting there for weeks. The Road So Far This journey started with an answer on Super User.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year&#39;s Resolutions - 2018</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/resolution-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/resolution-2018/</guid>
      <description>Woah, 2017 flew by. I may not have achieved everything on my New Year&amp;amp;rsquo;s Resolutions listfrom last year, but it did help me focus some of my efforts and I&amp;rsquo;m glad I put the list together.
To start off 2018, let&amp;rsquo;s revisit see what (if anything) got completed and set a new list for a new year.
2017, With Hindsight One blog post a month. The only month I didn&amp;rsquo;t do a post was February, but otherwise I&amp;rsquo;m happy with the frequency of posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KovertKringle: Secret Santa With a Dash of PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/kovertkringle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 03:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/kovertkringle/</guid>
      <description>Given it&amp;rsquo;s the holiday season, I recently spent about 3 hours live streaming the development of a PowerShell based Secret SantaOrganizer. You can watch the videos from these streams, if you&amp;rsquo;re so inclined, over on YouTube.
I can&amp;rsquo;t live with giving my projects straight forward names; with that in mind let&amp;rsquo;s check out KovertKringle.
Slow down… what&amp;rsquo;s a Secret Santa? If you&amp;rsquo;ve never done it before, Secret Santa basically boils down to a group of people who are each assigned another member of the group to buy a present for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding DateTime Headaches</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/datetime-headache/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 08:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/datetime-headache/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a number of things that - as a non-American - can cause confusion when dealing with America:
Imperial rather than Metric units of measurement, Words missing the letter &amp;lsquo;U,&amp;rsquo; Tipping, Backwards dates. A number of these applies to systems or software developed in America. The last one specifically, dates, is the subject of this short post.
When dates don&amp;rsquo;t go as planned Before getting into things, I wanted to thanks Dan Blankfor inspiring this post during a conversation we had on Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/psblogweek-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/psblogweek-recap/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday was the end of the latest #PSBlogWeek. It was a great event, with five days worth of awesome PowerShell content coming out!
This is my recap of the week, with links to all of the articles (and bloggers) and my main takeaways.
Monday Automating Chocolatey package internalizing with PowerShellby Dan FranciscusFirst up on Monday, Dan discussed tooling for automating the process of getting Chocolateypackages loaded into your company&amp;rsquo;s private repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Storage Reports With PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/powershell-storage-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/powershell-storage-report/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of the #PSBlogWeekPowerShell blogging series. #PSBlogWeek is a regular event where anyone interested in writing great content about PowerShell is welcome to volunteer. The purpose is to pool our collective PowerShell knowledge together over a 5-day period and write about a topic that anyone using PowerShell may benefit from. #PSBlogWeek is a Twitter hashtag, so feel free to stay up to date on the topic on Twitter at the #PSBlogWeekhashtag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BurntToast Breaking Change: Hiding Customizable AppID</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/burnttoast-no-appid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/burnttoast-no-appid/</guid>
      <description>I hate reducing customizability, just as much as I hate making breaking changes in my projects.
Unfortunately, BurntToasthas been making use of a bug to display Toast Notifications in Windows 10 despite it not being a UWP app. The Fall Creators Update appearsto be patching this bug and people running Insider builds have already noted that BurntToast isn&amp;rsquo;t functioning like they&amp;rsquo;re used to.
What was the bug? First, I should point out that Microsoft&amp;amp;rsquo;s guidancehas always been that for a desktop application (or in this case a script) to display a Toast Notification, you must have a shortcut in the start menu with an AppUserModeId (Referred to in this post as AppId.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October: The Hackiest Month of the Year</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/oct-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/oct-17/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a few things happening this month that officially make it the &amp;ldquo;hackiest&amp;rdquo; month of the year. I know&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s next to no creativity in that title considering it&amp;rsquo;s 100% ripped from one of the month&amp;rsquo;s events.
This is a very short post promoting three things coming up in October. I&amp;rsquo;m excited for them and you should be too!
Summit Session Acceptance The Call for Topicsfor next year&amp;rsquo;s PowerShell and DevOps Global Summitclosed today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recurrence Patterns and PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/recurrence-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/recurrence-pattern/</guid>
      <description>I love scheduling PowerShell scripts. I&amp;rsquo;ve got a server whose sole job in life is to be the place where my scripts are stored and executed on various schedules.
There&amp;rsquo;s one thing that bugs me when managing this from the prompt, however: Recurrence.
For once, the GUI is king?! When setting up a task via the Task Scheduler, you have the option of triggering once a month. Not just on the &amp;ldquo;15th of every month,&amp;rdquo; but also on the &amp;ldquo;third Wednesday of every month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The War on Passwords</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/war-on-passwords/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/war-on-passwords/</guid>
      <description>A little over a year ago, the United States National Institute for Standards and Technology (NIST) released a draft of SP 800-63 &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Digital Identity Guidelines&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;. These guidelines were finalized in June. I first found out about NIST&amp;rsquo;s guidelines via Sophosand it really captured my imagination.
(Yes, I&amp;rsquo;m including a few hyperlinks in this post. Consider them references and additional reading if you&amp;rsquo;re want to find out more.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting Windows Updates in 2017: The Lab Setup</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/wu-2017-revisit-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/wu-2017-revisit-setup/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been nine months since I last looked into preventing Windows Update related reboots in Windows 10. It feels like so much has changed since then and a recent commentmade me realize there is more to test.
With that in mind, I&amp;rsquo;m rebuilding my lab and will be introducing test cases over time. This will be a very short post detailing the first two test cases and how you can follow along with the results as they come about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office 365 &amp; PowerShell: Connecting All the Pieces</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/o365-all-the-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/o365-all-the-things/</guid>
      <description>Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve figured out how to connectto each of the Office 365 services, it&amp;rsquo;s time to tie a pretty (PowerShell) blue bow on it. If you just want to skip the writeup and see the result, you can check out the Gist. This Gist may get updates in the future.
Disclaimer The script created in this post is not a complete solution.
It is very much a starting point with no error handling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office 365 &amp; PowerShell: Jacking Into the Matrix</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/o365-connect/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/o365-connect/</guid>
      <description>One thing became apparent very quickly during my recent foray into Office 365: it truly is one big amalgam of bunch of Microsoft products. Just like their on-premises counterparts, each of these products has their own PowerShell interface for management.
Almost every module in the courseware for the &amp;ldquo;Enabling and Managing Office 365&amp;rdquo; course includes a &amp;ldquo;this is the thing you need to download&amp;rdquo; and/or &amp;ldquo;these are the PowerShell commands you need to run to connect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Office 365 Training: Navigating the Minefield</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/o365-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/o365-training/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a lot of research around Office 365 and Azure over the past couple of weeks. As a fan of video training, and as a Pluralsightsubscriber, I&amp;rsquo;ve been devouring the Pluralsight library.
One thing I&amp;rsquo;ve had to become good at very quickly is figuring out the age of the content I&amp;rsquo;m watching and deciding whether it&amp;rsquo;s still relevant.
Unlike traditional (on-premises) technologies, you can&amp;rsquo;t tell from a title whether you&amp;rsquo;re studying the latest version (Exchange 2016 vs Exchange 2013 for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crouton #4 – Getting Your Head Around Headers</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-headers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-headers/</guid>
      <description>Headers are a new option for toast notifications introduced in the Creators Update for Windows 10. They are used for the organization of toasts, and are supported from version 0.6.0 of the BurntToastPowerShell module and beyond.
Creating a Header Unlike the clickable toaststhat we discussed in the last croutonpost, you can use the &amp;ldquo;basic&amp;rdquo; New-BurntToastNotification function for toasts with headers, however you will need to use the New-BtHeader function to create the header object (which you can then re-use for multiple toasts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crouton #3 - Sometimes You Just Want to Click Your Toast</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-clickable/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-clickable/</guid>
      <description>Buttons, as we have discussed previously, are all well and good. However, if you&amp;rsquo;re only adding one to your toast, they can look a little… out of place if not outright ugly.
Surelyyou can just set an action on the toast itself, making it clickable?
Before we jump in, I&amp;rsquo;m aware that I&amp;rsquo;ve been terrible about mentioning the PowerShell module these posts rely on, and linking to other relevant info.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crouton #2 - You Can&#39;t Stop Progress (Bars)</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-progress-bars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-progress-bars/</guid>
      <description>April saw the release of the Creators Update for Windows 10 which brought with it a handful of new options for toast notifications. This post will serve as a quick rundown for one of these new options: Progress Bars.
A note before we get started, the examples below require version 0.6.0 of the BurntToast module.
Creating a progress bar Progress bars are created using a dedicated function, New-BTProgressBar, the resultant object can then be passed to New-BurntToastNotification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Always Ask for the API</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/always-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/always-api/</guid>
      <description>Take this hypothetical, totally-didn&amp;rsquo;t-recently-come-up-at-work, scenario: your business uses two disparate cloud services and needs them to share data, but they don&amp;rsquo;t integrate natively.
You, the scripting magician that you are, can take an export from the first service, manipulate it however it needs to be manipulated and then import it to the other service. You could do this in reverse. You could do this all day, every day; it&amp;rsquo;s a task right up your alley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crouton #1 - Toast Notifications for New Stack Overflow Questions</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-stackwatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/crouton-stackwatch/</guid>
      <description>Last week I pushed an update for the BurntToastPowerShell module to the PowerShell Gallery. This update, version 0.5.2, exposed the ability to add custom buttons to your toast notifications instead of just the standard Snooze and Dismiss option from previous versions.
This dramatically increases the flexibility and usability of these PowerShell generated toasts.
In an effort to show off the cool things you can accomplish with BurntToast, and to demo new features as they come out, I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing a series of ‘Croutons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reporting on Trello Boards with PowerTrello</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/trello-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 01:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/trello-report/</guid>
      <description>At work we&amp;rsquo;ve recently ramped up our use of Trelloto manage our tasks. It&amp;rsquo;s great, and I recommend anyone that works with lists of any description to give it a look. The only problem is, how does one show off the work the team has coming up, what they&amp;rsquo;re working on, and what they have ticked off?
You could just bring the Trello board up on a TV or laptop, but nothing distracts a room full of nerds faster than technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DHCP Reservations: No Cluster? No Problem!</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/dhcp-reservations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 01:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/dhcp-reservations/</guid>
      <description>Have multiple DHCP servers that aren&amp;rsquo;t in a cluster? Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, there are more people in this boat than you might think.
From time to time you&amp;rsquo;ll need to convert a lease into a reservation, but how do you go about making sure your clients reliably pick up their DHCP reservations (regardless of which DHCP server responds first)?
Just copy the reservations! Ergh, but that sounds like a lot of work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year&#39;s Resolutions - 2017</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/resolution-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 01:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/resolution-2017/</guid>
      <description>New Year&amp;rsquo;s Resolutions are the in thing, right? Since one of mine is to blog more… I might as well turn my resolutions for 2017 into a post. If you&amp;rsquo;ve been here in the past, you know my slant, this list will be PowerShell heavy.
The list, in no particular order despite the numbers </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Josh King, &#39;IT Pro,&#39; and This Is How I Work</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/how-i-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/how-i-work/</guid>
      <description>I follow a bunchof people on GitHub and make checking timeline/feed on there part of my morning habit.
You never know what little gems you&amp;rsquo;ll see come upon, from leaders in your area(s) of interest starring an interesting repo to great coders creating a brand new repo for an awesome new project.
This morning (as in&amp;hellip; the morning of the day I started writing this post) Adam Bertramcreated a new repo called &amp;amp;ldquo;HowIWorkIT&amp;amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digging Up Old Blog Posts</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/old-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/old-posts/</guid>
      <description>I was recently looking through my Google Analytics and noticed there was an old blogspot address that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen in years.
The blog only had two posts on it, and judging by the title (and my job at the time) I was obviously looking at starting a Helpdesk orientated site.
Time sure has flown by since then.
Rather than just let the (short) posts die, I figure I&amp;rsquo;d repost them here (for the lulz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell Updateable Help Frustration</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/updatable-help-frustration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/updatable-help-frustration/</guid>
      <description>AAAAAAAAAAAAARRGH!
I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to brute force my way through this for a little over 24 hours now, and I&amp;rsquo;m afraid I&amp;rsquo;ll have to admit defeat.
I was playing around with the platyPSmodule to generate markdown and external help for my BurntToastmodule. It&amp;rsquo;s a very short leap from there to updateable help.
And honestly, once you have external help files it is actually a very simple process to get updatable help in place and working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on Windows Update... Up Time</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/win-10-update-up-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/win-10-update-up-time/</guid>
      <description>Three weeks ago, I started up an experimentto find out if an old SuperUser answerof mine was still valid.
The TL;DR of the previous post was:
VMs built running Professional and Enterprise editions of Windows 10, version 1607. PowerShell script is running to collect a screenshot of the VMs every hour. These screenshots also show system uptime. So, it rebooted right? Nope. Three weeks (nearly) later, and we still haven&amp;rsquo;t had a reboot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Validating Prevention of Automatic Reboots on Windows 10, Version 1607</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/wu-windows-1607/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/wu-windows-1607/</guid>
      <description>Over a year ago, I answered a questionon Super User. The question was about stopping the very persistent Windows Update from rebooting without the users&amp;rsquo; consent, and wow was that ever a popular topic. The question is up to about 91K views, and my answer is rapidly approaching 100 up votes.
Since then there has been a number of large updates to Windows 10, chief among them being the Anniversary Update, after which there has been a lot of conflicting reports of whether or not the ‘fix&amp;rsquo; still worked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatically Shutting Down My Home Server, so I Don&#39;t Have To</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/home-server-shutdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/home-server-shutdown/</guid>
      <description>My home server, nestled behind the TV, is an old HP workstation. It&amp;rsquo;s not exactly what I&amp;rsquo;d call&amp;hellip; power efficient.
In an effort to not consume too much power I try to shut it down every night, but if I wasn&amp;rsquo;t actively using it before bed I would often forget about it.
The boxes main duty is to act as a Plexserver and over time I have come to realise that if I&amp;rsquo;m not watching something by about 8:30 at night then I won&amp;rsquo;t be using it at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Very Octocat U2F Key</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/u2f-key/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 00:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/u2f-key/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this month GitHub announced, in partnership with Yubico, that they now support FIDO Universal 2nd Factor (U2F) as an option for two-factor authentication alongside their existing support for Google/Microsoft Authenticator Apps. With the announcement came a special offer: a special edition, Octocat adorned, Yubico U2F key for only $5!
A deal too good to pass up, especially as someone that has around ten services listed in their phone&amp;rsquo;s Authenticator app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving ValidateScript a Makeover</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/ugly-validation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/ugly-validation/</guid>
      <description>I Feel Validated One of the awesome things you get when adding the CmdletBinding attributeto you functions (you are including CmdletBinding, right?) is the ability to use Parameter Validation Atributes. These atributes include nifty options like allowing or disallowing null values, specifying a valid amount of items that an aray parameter can accept, specifying a set of pre-determined valid values.
All of these are awesome, and save you a fair amount of work in manually validating user input before using it within the rest of the function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mini Post: 20 More Pulseway Alerts with PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/more-alerts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/more-alerts/</guid>
      <description>The Pitch In my last postI showed how you could extend the possible alerts generated by Pulsewaywith PowerShell and Windows&amp;rsquo; Event Log.
The example used, checking to see if a disk was present within the operating system, was just the tip of the iceberg (and rather mundane.)
In this mini post I&amp;rsquo;ll list 20 more ideas for PowerShell fuelled Pulseway alerts.
Disclaimer from last post: Be careful about over saturating yourself with notifications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>With PowerShell, Pulseway Can Alert on Anything</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/pulseway-all-the-alerts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/pulseway-all-the-alerts/</guid>
      <description>The Pitch Need to monitor some servers (and/or workstations)? Pulsewayis a good solution. The configuration of what you want alerts on is as simple as putting checks in boxes. Need to know when someone logs into your server? Check Need to know when someone installs something on your server? Check Need to know when your servers CPU is pegged at 100%? Check Need to know when your servers data drive is running out of free space?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Splatting your way to reduced duplicated code</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/ps-splatting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/ps-splatting/</guid>
      <description>Splattingis a great way of making cmdlet calls with a lot of parameters more legible. You create a hashtable of of the parameter names and their values, which you can format nicely, and pass the hashtable to the cmdlet.
A good example of this in action from the TechNet magazineis turning:
{% highlight powershell %} Get-WmiObject –computername SERVER-R2 –class Win32_LogicalDisk –filter &amp;ldquo;DriveType=3&amp;rdquo; –credential &amp;ldquo;Administrator&amp;rdquo; {% endhighlight %}
into:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repairing Trust Relationships Without a Reboot</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/trust-no-reboot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/trust-no-reboot/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s hopefully not something that comes up often, but if you work in a Windows environment you will undoubtedly come across machines with trust relationship issues with the domain. Maybe it was an overeager High Availability action on a vSphere guest resulting in two copies of the same server running at once. Or perhaps it was a helpdesk technician powering up a cloned desktop while connected to the network. Suddenly you can&amp;rsquo;t get onto the machine using your domain credentials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Single Most Important Resource When Learning Windows PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/ps-important-resource/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.toastit.dev/blog/ps-important-resource/</guid>
      <description>So you&amp;rsquo;ve decided to learn Windows PowerShell. You&amp;rsquo;re probably reading a fair share of blogs, forums and even books. Maybe there is a specific task you&amp;rsquo;re trying to complete and have found out that PowerShell is the only avenue to do so. Or maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve heard a lot about PowerShell, and it&amp;rsquo;s ever increasing functionality within Windows, and are curious about how you can make it work for you in your day job.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
